Inventory of the Burwell Papers 1853-1911
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Burwell Papers, 1853-1911.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
230 pieces.
Papers of the Burwell Family.
Burwell Family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, October 14, 1938.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of the Burwell family of Powhatan County and Richmond, Va.
Arrangement
Arrangement
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Organization
Inventory has been arranged into three series. Series 1 are letters, series 2-4 are papers concerning a trusteeship, home improvements, and the valuation of furniture. The final series (series 5) are invoices, receipts, notes and canceled checks.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Confederate States of America. Army. Virginia Infantry Regiment, 8th.
Persons:
Burwell family.; Burwell, Blair, 1858- 1882.
Geographical Names
Turkey Island (Va.: Estate)
Contents List
  Series 1: Letters
- Letters 1853-1911
  - Marshall Hall, Jr., at Charleston [S.C.], to Blair Burwell, at Richmond, Va. 15 Dec[ember] 1853. (Folder 1)
  - [?] to Jennie [?]. 1 Jan[uary] 1857. (Folder 1)
  - Jenny [?] at Rockbridge Baths, to Dr. Blair Burwell, at Richmond, Va. 10 July 1857. (Folder 1)
  - B[lair] B[urwell] at Richmond, to Jenny [?] 21 July 1858. (Folder 1)
  - B[lair] B[urwell], Head Quarters, Pickett's Division, to Jenny B[urwell]. 26 May 1864. (Folder 1)
  - William [?], at Montpellier, to Dr. Blair Burwell, at Richmond. 29 Oct. 1872. (Folder 1)
    Postmarked Powhatan.
  - Blair Burwell, at Richmond, to Jenny [Burwell]. 14 Sept. 1874. (Folder 1)
  - . R. Boggs, Jr. at Blacksburg, Va. to Dr. [Blair] Burwell. 17 Jan[uary] 1877. (Folder 1)
  - W. P. Burwell at Richmond to Mal[?] 8 Oct[ober] 1877.
  - A. Johnston to Dr. Blair Burwell. 29 April 1878. (Folder 1)
    Enclosure: Map of the city of Washington [D.C.]
  - Andrew Johnston at Richmond, Va. to Dr. Blair Burwell, at Richmond, Va. 13 May 1881. (Folder 1)
  - V. B. P[?] at White Sulpher [Sulphur Springs, W.Va.] to Dr. Blair Burwell, at Richmond, Va. 12 July 1881. (Folder 1)
  - C.S. Johnson at Richmond, Va. to Dr. Burwell. 16 Dec[ember] 1883. (Folder 1)
  - Sally [Pickett], at Washington to Robert Burwell at Tobaccoville, Powhatan County, Va. 26 May 1911. (Folder 1)
  - B[lair] B[urwell] at Richmond, to Jenny [? n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Blair [Burwell] to his father, [?] Burwell n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Martha B[urwell] to Jenny [Burwell]. n.d. (Folder 1)
  - V. B. P[?] to [?] n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Pansy [?] to Mrs. Robert P. Burwell, at Tobaccoville, Powhatan County, Virginia. n.d., Postal card. (Folder 1)
  Series 2: Trustee Papers
- Trustee Papers 1855-1892., 20 pieces. (Folder 2)
  Papers concerning the trusteeship for the benefit of Mrs. Virginia B. Burwell and her children, including papers relating to the Turkey Island estate in Henrico County, Virginia.
  Series 3: Burwell Home Improvements
- Papers concerning improvements to the home of Dr. Blair Burwell 1882, 10 pieces. (Folder 2)
  Papers concerning improvements to the home of Dr. Blair Burwell, Grace and 4th Streets, Richmond, Va.
  Series 4: Furniture Valuation
- Valuation of furniture, plate, etc. held by Andrew Johnston as trustee for Mrs. V. B. Burwell. Also valuation of Miss Olivia Johnston's property. n.d., 1 piece. (Folder 2)
  Series 5: Invoices, etc.
- Invoices, etc. n.d. (Folder 2)
  Invoices, receipts, notes, canceled checks.
  - Miss Burwell. 1883-1884. (Folder 3)
  - Blair Burwell estate. 1836-1837., 32 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Blair Burwell, Jr. 1867-1881., 83 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Dr. Blair Burwell. 1870-1885. (Folder 32 pieces.)
  - H. DeB. Burwell. 1883-1884., 2 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Mary Burwell. 1884, 4 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Virginia B. Burwell. 1883-1917., 10 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - William R. Burwell. 1864-1882., 6 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Other persons. 1838-1874., 6 pieces. (Folder 3)
  - Envelopes. n.d., 6 pieces. (Folder 3)